# Ali Zaib

alizaib.azr@gmail.com 3400792449 Sadiqui Street House# 3 Morr Samanabad Lahore, Punjab Pakistan

#### Summary

Skilled Php Laravel developer and team leader with diverse experience utilizing php tools for client-server environments and fluid understanding of many programming languages including Python JavaScript, Jquery, Vue.js and designing technologies HTML CSS Boostrap, and experience in selenium automation testing. Worked with Large Teams, maintain and improve company projects. Worked on critical business applications.

#### Education

## Bahauddin Zakariya University, Multan

BSCS • Multan, Punjab 12/2018

CGPA 3.0/4.0

#### **Professional Skills**

- · PHP
- Python
- · Vanilla Javascript
- JQuery
- HTML

- Laravel
- Selenium
- · Vue.is
- Git Flow
- Mysql

## **Employment History**

## **DreamsTech Solution**

Laravel developer • Lahore, Punjab

12/2018 - 03/2019

- Development of new applications and maintenance of existing ones in Laravel.
- Payment methods integration.
- · Reporting and breakdown management.
- Develop UIs with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Wrote SQL queries to retrieve data from the database.

## **Programmers Force**

Mid Level Software developer • Lahore, Punjab

04/2019 - 11/2020

- · Worked on blockchain-based application
- Development of new features in the application.
- Code optimization and revisions.
- API development and third-party API integrations.
- API automation Testing
- Development of Front-end Automation Scripts.
- · Query Optimization.
- Development of front-end screens.

## **Seers Digital**

Senior Full Stack Developer • Lahore, Punjab

11/2020 - Present

- Implementation of Queues and Jobs
- Implementation of API authentication system using a passport.
- Deployment of Applications on EC2.

- Back-end APIs Development in Laravel.
- Code refactoring and improvements.
  Development of Front-end single-page applications. in Vue.js.
  Vue.js SPA integrations with FireStore.

Languages

• English

• Urdu